This content was generated by AI

FILL Kick Off at Bayview Glen - Discussion


Chris (Coach) (00:10)
So we're going to start today just by deep briefing. What happened on Sunday. Because everybody went to different activities, so we want to share the knowledge with everybody. So when you're sharing what you learned, I want to know the workshop that you learned it at, if you know the name of the presenter who it was, so you're citing the resource, so we can use that as well and reference later, and what you learned that you want to share with the group that you think will help the team that makes sense to everybody. Okay, so We'll start with, so what did you learn at the LL challenge kickoff? 

In the morning sessions who wants to go first with their the first thing, but they did okay. 

Ira  (01:07)
So our first thing that we did was I forget the name, but it was called how to build a functional robot 

And Basically, it wasn't really that helpful like they pretty much just explained everything we already knew. But Fyodor took the notes that And then 

Chris  (01:28)
Okay, Fedor, can you share what? What useful tips they had or reinforced? What we're already doing is, right? 

Fedor  (01:37)
If that the Robot could take square to a wall and also it like the other senses. 

Chris  (01:48)
What was that? 

Ira (01:49)
It Shields like light from color sensors, so it doesn't sense the wrong thing. Also. A small, weird, small wheels have less Weber and more accuracy, so you should probably use them because accuracy is more important than speed. 

Chris  (02:08)
Okay. 

Ira  (02:16)
That's basically it 

Chris  (02:18)
Anything about attachments? 

Ira (02:20)
You know, if they didn't actually talk about it. 
 
They like they had, they showed a bunch of attachments, but they didn't really talk about them. 

Chris  (02:28)
Okay, well, when we look at our robot, we scored it. For how well did we all lines it? We'll just go round with everybody's first cot. 

Fedor (02:41)
This like the trailing wheels, those have no rubber. The wheels, we should probably use the ball because it's the basketball, there are no friction and also 

Ira (02:52)
And it turns the best 

Frdor  (02:53)
Yeah, it like it has like it has like really the turning, no friction, and it's such very small. 

Chris  (02:59)
 so How would you score our robot based on the design? So mention every one? 

By one, the things that you would want to investigate or change to the team. 

Fedor (03:14)
So 

Chris (03:15)
You already mentioned. 

Fedor (03:20)
If we can probably remove those 

Chris  (03:24)
And okay, so change the front wheel for a ball. What about squaring up? Are we good or 

Fedor  (03:29)
Yeah, I could. 

Ira (03:30)
It's pretty good, I mean it's really all they really need was a cream around the bottom, because that's where their sensors were, but like, also, it's, I think it's good to the thing with the box is that there's not a lot of parts spots to attach things. And I think this has good 

Chris  (03:48)
Okay? And what about the shielding of the light? Do you think that that 

Ira  (03:51)
Yeah, I think it's good. 

Fedor  (03:52)
We don't use a lot of color sensors but like it worked fine when there wasn't something covered. 

Chris  (03:59)
Okay, thank you 

All right, programming 101 Okay, who can share what they learned at programming? 

Brynn  (04:09)
Oh, this one is a good Okay, there are different types of rocks. Flat blocks are found in, we just read in the oh I bet that's found maybe I should read this. 

Amelia  (04:27)
So we weren't about different types of blocks. 

Turns 

Chris  (04:32)
What are those 4 types of terms like 

Amelia  (04:35)
They always told use a point turn 

Chris (04:38)
How do you do a point turn 

Amelia  (04:40)
You leave one wheel stopped and one wheel run. No, yes, no I don't even remember, and there's a pivot turn, there's an arc turn. 

Chris  (04:51)
Have you do an ark turn? 

Amelia  (04:56)
I'm asking, but it's One wheel goes forwards when wheel goes backward

Chris  (05:03)
That's a pivot, yeah? 

Brynn  (05:06)
It's kind of like you're going straight and you're turning, it's like an arc when war wheels like a b******. 

Chris  (05:13)
Yes, so both wheels are going in the same direction, but one goes faster. That's the argument, okay, what else 

Amelia  (05:21)
We learned about using a sensor white sensor but we already kind of knew that, so it was over here, an overview of everything. 

Brynn  (05:32)
What they were really nice. 

Amelia  (05:33)
I never know everyone. Oh, yeah? 

Chris  (05:37)
 Okay, so that was the turns. 

So you have more confidence to make programming changes. 

Brynn  (05:55)
Yeah, it was kind of just a confidence together with that. Yeah, cool 

Amelia  (05:59)
I have a comment yes, you know that we actually can switch out. When during the whole game? Yeah, like yeah. 

Like, for example, say, this is the table, the two people are here. The two people are here. You can, they can't switch, but the table laugh. 


Brynn  (06:17)
Is there a confusing last year? 

Amelia  (06:18)
they said, we couldn't, 

Chris  (06:21)
We're at the place we did the tournament was a it was a first year doing so maybe they didn't know. Okay, but that's all about adapting to thank you, mom. Situation, okay, programming 201. 

Jack (06:39)
So what we learned in programming too, at once was as one shows types of line followings, so we learned how to do 2 stage line following, which is where you have one color sensor and if that color sensor sees black. 

Then, we'll turn to the right. And if it sees white, it will turn to the left that way, your robot kind of like zigzags across the line, and then we also learn how to do a yaw terms of yeah, okay. Oh, it was um, how do square up the square? 

Which we needed 2 color sensors for so after the 

After we came back from the school, we added 2 color sensors on the robot, because before there was just one of the other here. So how that worked is once one of the color sensors sees black. Let's say the left one sees black. 

The robot will turn like this until the right one sees black, and then it will kind of just jiggle until it gets straight app with the black line. I think both of these are very helpful especially to us, because if somebody that is lining up the robot in a competition, then they accidentally, maybe turn it a little bit if you use squirrel or toothstone following it will kind of like. Mel my itself up, so you don't have to. 

Jordan (08:10)
So I'm it's okay if you make a little mistake. Okay, also, this year I'm gone Warren. So it's other more useful. 


Chris  (08:20)
Yeah, there's some lines right in front of models that would be useful to square up. Okay so who was it that gave you that tip was his name? 

Jack  (08:31)
Um, Harrison. Here is Dino. Harrison got Harrison kansino @gmail.com. 

Chris  (08:40)
Yeah, so Harrison and programming 21 taught you about squaring up and then you looked at the robot, and you saw we only had one color sensor remember, we tested it in the gym, and we couldn't square up, so you came back and you changed the robot to have 2 color sensors, all right, Turkey. Correct, turke. Okay. 

And the next, what did you guys go to? 

Brynn (09:10)
The equity, oh yeah, that's Wall Street equity. 

Chris  (09:13)
Passing equity includes a team, so why don't you tell 

Brynn  (09:16)
It was actually really fun. Yeah, you know, yeah 

Amelia  (09:20)
This whole thing was really fun. It's about 

So let's, I'm gonna use an example. Let's say Alexis. It's really Talkative, we talkative and Brynn she has a really good idea, but she's like, hey, shall we share? 

Brynn  (09:42)
Okay, so what Alexis would help me say what I need to say? And 

Amelia  (09:50)
Yeah, and also, we talked about the difference between equity and inclusion. Inclusion was bringing people in and giving everyone the 

Brynn (09:57)
Same amount of stuff, but equity is making sure everybody gets the same, so experience themselves. 

Chris  (10:04)
In fact, so there's some good things there we could use in our group work right 

Amelia (10:08)
What about sexism. 

Chris  (10:15)
Do you want to share it. 

Amelia (10:17)
So they took all yeah. It's okay, yeah. 

We don't need to get into that. 

Brynn  (10:27)
But it was basically just about like, what inclusivity looks like, no inclusivity. No I know, but they had what inclusivity they had, like some, what's they called? So we had, you know, how we had dots on our faces. 

Amelia  (10:41)
Yeah, so yeah they gave us little dots, and you basically, you know, they were telling you to like, get into groups. And then afterwards they showed us photos of different circles with dots inside of them, and what each I guess, like one circle means. 

Brynn (10:57)
Yeah, one was exclusion. 

So it was like a bunch of yellow dots and a bunch of colorful dots outside. 

Amelia  (11:02)
When was like one? 

Brynn  (11:06)
One was like. 

Amelia (11:07)
One was like, one was like inclusion, and it was everything. It was all the docks, but they were in a little circle and yellow dots were my mom. 

Brynn (11:15)
Will I decide? No, that was that was separate case, segregation segregation, and then there was also like exclusivity, which was like yellow dots in the big circle, and then all the other docks around the border of it that's exclusion, yeah, exclusion. 

Chris  (11:32)
Yeah, okay, so let's look for those things, and if we see them happening in our day-to-day, then we make a change, right? And we yes, and we get closer together. Okay, great. 

And then robot mission and rules explain is that you guys, yeah 

Ira  (11:51)
Yeah It was kind of 

That was like beginners of first legal league. Yeah 

Fedor  (12:00)
All the stuff needed was really just for beginners like it was like everything they said. 

Chris  (12:06)
Not for provincial qualifying teams like we are. 

Fedor  (12:13)
I realized I inspect and inspection bonus. 

Ira (12:18)
Like, you can always Lago. 

We Figured out to like swap out and switch with someone you know, we were allowed to ask the ref to change the certain mission positions that are allowed to be changed, like 3 missions. Okay, don't like you can ask the, ref, don't take 

Chris (12:38)
That has to be before the men start. You 

Ira (12:41)
Okay so taste good or anything that last point, yeah like, yeah, I get there right now for the seeds tank, the top seed should go on master first goes the light seed that's not attached to the like 3 and then the middle seed goes boy, yeah, on the right, sun goes on and then the top one 

Ira (13:08)
Okay, so that order matters. 

And then if you doesn't say you can't do something you probably can do it, and also probably too you can't. He said, he said our rules that it doesn't say you can't do it, you can do 

Chris (13:20)
And what was the rule change with the bugs 

Ira  (13:23)
Oh, yeah? 

Fedor  (13:26)
You always check updates, okay. Because even though it's like if we, if passed to the rentals, they can make an update like 5 days before and if we don't check it, it might be like harder for us. 

Chris  (13:39)
So, do you know his name, who was running? Did you get a good 

Ira (13:44)
He was like the head of provincial. 

Fedor  (13:45)
I remember. 

He was a correct referee. 

Ira (13:49)
The guy has like trains. 

Fedor  (13:50)
Don't be like the referee, you trains the referee who trains like 

Chris (13:54)
Was he Jeff Lockheed? 


Fedor  (14:02)
He said, Jeff, he said his name is Jeff, and I saw it. It has an owl next to one of them. 

Chris  (14:07)
You guys and you guys, it was the Edmund Kim and the pink titans for the end of the 

Ira  (14:15)
There was also, like, if once the like don't move the robot or anything like, don't move anything until all the points are being hunted. Because then you'll probably like lose. 

Chris  (14:25)
Yeah, it's good to tip and verify your score without touching it. So don't get too excited at the end of the day. 

Fedor (14:31)
And I don't shake the table if we win, because I think I like knock off a mission and then we could guess that one. 

Brynn  (14:38)
Guys, I've went with Alexis, I have more aS WELL. 

Chris  (14:45)
Why don't you share your notes for that one as well? 

Alexis  (14:47)
Okay. 

Brynn  (14:48)
And so it would be trust 

Amelia  (14:50)
I have a note. Don't touch the table. 

Brynn  (14:53)
Robotics, okay, so basically the mantises are gonna be moved forward. They're not going to be a steak off. They're gonna randomize the cykada

Chris  (15:03)
What we know which one is where we see them, we have to close our eyes, or what 

Brynn  (15:07)
Oh, they're just gonna randomize them, like it's gonna be in one spot and they're just gonna do it. And And then then the snuck, snack. and then the robot is like the main character, so like, as long as the rule you know, like it just needs to complete the task. 

Brynn  (15:21)
As long as it's following the rules like it doesn't have to be done in a certain way. It's just as long as it's bivulates. 

Chris (15:29)
Okay, anything else yep. 

Amelia  (15:34)
So, you know, the mission was 

The ones with the slog and the ones that the spy don't touch, those goes down. 

Chris (15:41)
Yeah, what do you lose points? Yeah? We can try to work 

Amelia  (15:47)
You can try to put this lug up, but 

Chris (15:50)
I don't think we'll do that, okay. And then you guys already did 201 and then, so now we go to the afternoon. 

Jack  (16:05)
What about PID? 

Chris  (16:07)
Oh, yeah, pid, so tell us about Jack and Jordan, tell us about pid and who presented and what you learned. 

Jack  (16:16)
So a man named Mr. Pye presented pin, he said that he calls him that he has his kids call him stuff back because he's had he's like a college teacher. I think or something like that, I'm don't know what a subject, though, because he thinks that like the number of pie is like a very good number, but that doesn't really matter anyways did is a way to make it. 

So when your robot does something like moving straight or following the line, it's more accurate. So How basically how you do it is, let's say you're doing 2 stage line following, and you're going off by a wall. And you're 

Since you're turning until you see a black on your robot's gonna do a lot of zigzags, and that might be slow and unaccurate, so what you can do is you can get a number called kp. 

And as long as you make it in the decimals, then instead of your robot turning, until it sees a color you can just have it. So when it turns it calculates on how much it turned incorrectly and then multiplies that by 0.3 or whatever your kg is, and then it will turn softer. Which means the longer a line follows, the closer it will get to just going straight. 

Jordan (17:42)
Which makes so your robots way less zigzaggy, and goes through the line cleaner and plaster. 

Chris  (17:51)
Okay, anything to add turn? Okay in the afternoon. Deodorant, Ira, you went to one thing in the afternoon, right? 

Ira  (18:03)
Yes, what was it? 

Fedor  (18:06)
It was an innovation project. 

Ira  (18:08)
I'm hard Jud. 

Chris  (18:09)
Okay, I how to prepare for a judging session by Calum Tsang. 

Yeah, okay, what did you learn from Calum? 

Ira  (18:18)
So this one's also worth your first time first. Yeah, like 

Fedor  (18:23)
We know this, but we're yeah, so 

Ira  (18:26)
He did give some good like tips finish, like how to get like kind of like a good robot explanation, you should probably say your favorite mission and explain how you did it and what everyone did to help to do that mission and what we do with my time, like, how did we like, how do we like upgrade the robot or build a new one or yeah. 

Chris  (18:55)
Yeah, we've already talked about some upgrades just today, right? Though you mentioned you want to switch to the ball, we've talked about the light sensors, the lining up. Yep, and then 

Ira  (19:07)
Yeah, again, like always to remember the rubric that we got last year. The like, the one that tells us about 

Fedor  (19:14)
About how they score We should probably always look at that to see how we can always score the most. 

IRa  (19:20)
I mean, but we look at that for years now describe, and like, describe how we did things like you detailed, well, I mean, where I knew that, but let's just see, describe how we did things like core values. We would like to code step-by-step like not for we step-by-step by step. Yeah, like you could like the brow, you can do. 

Fedor  (19:40)
I feel like that. I'll follow the color 

Ira  (19:43)
First and then he told us to be like, can I suck up to the judges like when we're leaving and be up like Like kind of like, be really encouraging to the other teams and our team and be like, thank you, and you know, yeah. 

I wrote be nice, but Fyodor told me to write suck up. And then one of his direct quotes was, don't trust AI. Start with Google and with real, let's see Google AI presentational Art, let's say I like how we must like to start the innovation project. 

Fedor  (20:21)
But AI, yeah, like he directly said, don't trust that. 

IRa (20:26)
Okay. 

Chris  (20:28)
It's a member last year. What it would do whenever we had an answer from AI. I checked the source. 

Yeah, so we'll do that again this year. Okay. 

Ira  (20:40)
I should do those little 

Chris  (20:42)
And then first, like A Girl

Brynn  (20:49)
First, like a girl, which is empowering a woman and young women and staff in stem, which is, it was like it was basically like it was made by this team in Orlando, Florida, the exploding bacon's Yeah, their lover was like a pig exploded rocket ship. Yeah, so like and there's like gas coming out of the rocket ship. 

Amelia  (21:14)
No, it's fire, it was fire in our gas. 

Brynn  (21:16)
And then there was the smoke of the fire. Yeah, anyway It wasn't really like about MO's robot stuff, but it was like we did learn things about fol. We did learn physically about fol., like they had trivia as well, which was Because they talked about Marie Curie 

Amelia  (21:43)
I think that like something radio active. 

Brynn  (21:45)
You are, yes, she found out about something radioactive. I don't even know what it's called. And then they also talked about like, what else can we talk about? 

Amelia  (21:55)
Well boy. Oh yeah, they had A. They talked about. 

Brynn  (21:58)
So their name is ConnecTech and basically, they have a YouTube channel, a website, a web Instagram, Facebook, Facebook tons of things. 

Chris  (22:10)
Okay, so you learned about ConnecTech, and they have an influencer page YouTube channel, so we should add them to our list of team resources. On the website, okay, YouTube page and a website. Okay, and so we'll research, connect tech and see if we can learn some things from Them and first like a girl, okay? 

And then programming 301 last 1. 

Jack  (22:36)
So we learned how to do like where robots start, like, start at a slower Pace, and then speeds up and then slows down again, so it's more accurate toleration. Yeah, and then And then you also learn another like gyro turn so it doesn't go like 

Things like that, instead of going like 

I also learned how to do a yaw turn so basically, instead of watches, turning 90° in the code you tell it to turn 90° in yaw that way if it messes up a little bit, the gyro sensor will like unmes it up, so it will make sure it's not big. And then what else do we do? 

Chris  (23:27)
What was the difference between 

Jack (23:29)
We learned how to do pim line following So basically like the one with Mr. Pi, we just learned what pid was and then in cook code in 301, we learned how to use pid to follow lines and go straight. 

Chris (23:48)
And I think they talked about, what's the difference between 90° of yah and 90° on the motor when you turn a wheel 90 

Jack
90° on Yale is like your robots, kind of like a compass now, where we will turn 90°, according to This the box on the motor on your wheel is 360. I'm gonna turn your view on 90°, so if you turn your view on 90°, it won't be as accurate because I'm trying to turn the wheel and not the robot 

Chris  (24:27)
Okay, anything else anyone wants to add from the Bayview Glenn kick off


Okay, so let's just move on. Okay. So the next for the next half an hour, we're gonna work on innovation, project ideas. 

so We're going to come up with, the goal is come up with a problem right, so like what is the very specific problem we would like to try and solve, we don't necessarily need to come up with the problem today. So today you can either come up with a topic or a problem or a topic with a problem or maybe a topic with many ideas of what a problem might be, you don't need to be sure that it's a problem, you could just be a guess, okay, and then between now and next Tuesday, we're gonna research those topics and ideas that you come up with and come up. 

With sources, and then we'll prove through sources, that whatever you thought was, a problem is really a problem. 

Okay? So So the output from today is topic and your guess at what the problem is so what would be an example of that like what would be a topic and a problem? Yeah 


Amelia  (27:39)
What is it called? What is it called? It's when an animal that's not native comes into a no invasive species species, and the problem is that invasive species are eating all the food and making other animals that are native die or then don't 

Chris  (28:01)
So the topic is invasive species, and the problem is that there's species Reduced biodiversity. Okay, so that's the idea. So you get into small groups or individuals up to you, write down your topic and the problem that you think exists and try and come up with, like 3 to 5 okay, and then we'll do that for 15-20 minutes. 

